Analytics is something every business requires to stay competitive.
市场营销是任何一家企业保持市场竞争力的必要手段
The more information you can use to inform your actions, the better.
获取到的市场信息越多 越能做出正确的业务决定
Analytics and the techniques to properly use them support
恰当地应用营销分析和手段 可以帮助业务方做出
both strategic marketing decisions such as how much to spend or what a customer is worth,
战略性市场决策 比如市场预算多少 客户价值是多少
and more tactical campaign decisions,
也能让市场营销活动更为效率
such as targeting the right customer with the right message at the right time.
比如 在正确的时间向正确的人群发送正确的信息
No matter what industry you're business is in,
不管你处在哪个行业
it's important to understand the information surrounding your market,
你都要去了解你的市场、
your competition, and the journey your customers take.
竞争者、客户旅程 (Customer Journey)
Marketing analytics benefits your entire organization and it's one of
市场分析有利于企业的整体业务
the most fundamental skills any marketer or business owner must hone.
是每个业务分析师、市场专员、甚至企业领导都必须掌握的技能
Now, I'm sure you're aware there's a lot of data available to us.
大家都知道 有大量的信息/数据围绕着市场
So it's important that we really measure what matters.
所以 我们应该只衡量那些对我们有用的信息
We have to go beyond getting those metrics,
我们不仅仅要知道有哪些指标
we must sort out how to take action with that data.
也要清楚如何根据指标表现来采取行动
We're going to spend a lot of time together talking about analytics,
接下来 我们会花大量时间来讲如何分析
so let's talk about our goals for what we're studying.
现在 我们先来谈谈接下来的学习内容
We want to learn how this data is collected and distributed.
首先是数据的收集与利用
Knowing where data comes from and how it's
知道数据的来源 以及如何整合数据
combined will help you understand how that data can be leveraged.
能让我们了解后续如何利用数据
You'll need to know where to look for this data,
你需要知道从哪里收集到数据
and then you'll be more sensitive around the concerns of how data is collected.
才会对 “如何收集数据及其风险” 这一问题保持相当的敏感度
We also want to understand the questions that we're trying to answer.
对于我们提出的业务问题 我们也需要深度了解 才能回答
Every business is trying to get the right message to the right users at the right time.
每家企业都希望在正确的时间给正确的人群发送正确的信息
Your message and your timing and your users are well different than mine.
因为每家企业的“时机”“目标人群”都是不一样的
So you'll have to be specific with
所以为了达成业务目标 你的业务问题一定要具体
We also want to understand the available metrics and how they're measured.
我们也会学习目前有哪些指标 以及如何衡量这些指标
In each channel, paid earned, and owned,
比如 在不同的推广渠道 包括付费推广、官方推广，粉丝推广
you'll have different metrics,
指标都是不一样的
and you need to know which are the most important.
你会需要知道对于特定渠道 哪些指标是我们需要关注的
You also want to understand how they're used so that way,
你也需要了解这些指标如何使用
you can figure out how to combine them to get better insights.
才能知道如何根据整体指标表现 发现业务洞察
We also want to figure out how to watch out for data reporting
我们也会学习如何警惕数据报表里的坑
pitfalls so we don't fall victim to common mistakes.
这样我们自己才不会掉进坑里
Next, we need to figure out what metrics are important for your business goals.
接下来 我们需要知道如何根据业务目标 选择合适的指标
You have all of this data coming in,
我们手头上可能有很多数据
but what data is actually important and actionable for your business.
但哪些数据才是重要的、有用的呢？
You need to be able to understand what data you're
从这一步到下一步 你会需要哪些信息呢？
From here, we want to understand how to apply these metrics to your business.
最后 我们也需要了解如何将指标应用于具体业务
Everything that we do in marketing analytics is about being actionable.
市场营销分析的最终产出是一个可执行的方案
We want to understand the information and create
我们希望根据信息来创作报告
reports that can be used to drive real decisions.
而这个报告是可以推动业务决策的
It's also important that we have confidence in reporting so that we can
在报告里 我们要对自己的数据、洞察有信息
take action on our analytics measurements and on the reporting we make.
以根据这些分析结果和报告结果 来推动执行
All kinds of decisions get made on this data and you're going to want
从数据可以推出各种结论 你需要对自己的结果有信心
the confidence that you've found the right information,
坚信自己找到了正确的信息
use it in the right way,
恰当地利用了这些信息
and made the right decisions.
同时做出了正确的决策
As you come to learn the foundations of marketing analytics,
学习完营销分析基础知识之后
you'll be better equipped to gather, analyze,
你就会知道该如何获取、分析、汇报数据
and report on the data you need to make better decisions.
最终做出决策